Love at first swipe
Electric Love is a comedy film directed by Aaron Fradkin.
Electric Love follows a group of 20-somethings as they
navigate the dating landscape of modern day L.A.
These interconnected stories feature young single people in various states of
courtship whether it’s a blind-date, hook-up or a long-term relationship.
The film explores straight, bisexual and gay
relationships as well as polyamory and monogamy.
In an increasingly technological world, our smartphones have become an integral part
of not only how we approach dating but how we connect with others.
Emma, played by Mia Serafino.
Adam, played by Zachary Mooren.
Officer Joi, played by Erik Griffin.
William, played by Kyle Howard.
Sarah, played by Hayley Marie Norman.
Greg Walsh, played by Matt Bush.
Electric Dreams is a 1984 science fiction romantic comedy film directed by Steve Barron
(in his feature film directorial debut) and written by Rusty Lemorande.
The film is set in San Francisco, focusing on a love triangle between an architect (Lenny Von Dohlen), a
cellist (Virginia Madsen), and a personal computer named Edgar (Bud Cort) that gains sentience.
The film was produced by Virgin Films, and is noted for its new wave soundtrack and
visual style, reflecting Barron's background as a music video director.
The score was composed by Giorgio Moroder, and the soundtrack
features the hit single "Together in Electric Dreams".
The narrative repeatedly has been cited as a modern retelling of the classic 1897 French play
Cyrano de Bergerac, exploring the intersection of human emotion and technology.
The film's premise reflected the cultural zeitgeist of the early 1980s, and its production coincided with Time magazine naming the
personal computer its "Machine of the Year" for 1982, signaling the technology's integration into domestic life.
Electric Dreams was released in the United States by MGM/UA Entertainment Co.
on July 20, 1984, and in the United Kingdom by
20th Century Fox on August 17, 1984.
It was a commercial disappointment and received mixed reviews from critics upon release, but
has since developed a cult following and drawn comparisons to the 2013 film Her.
The tone is lighthearted.